… where crime is a family affair.
State of Grace is a drama, crime, thriller film directed by Phil Joanou.
Hell's Kitchen, New York.
Terry Noonan returns home after a ten-year absence.
He soon reconnects with Jackie, a childhood friend and member of the Irish mob,
and rekindles his love affair with Jackie's sister Kathleen.
Terry, played by Sean Penn.
Frankie, played by Ed Harris.
Jackie, played by Gary Oldman.
Kathleen, played by Robin Wright.
Nick, played by John Turturro.
Finn, played by Burgess Meredith.
State of Grace is a 1990 American neo-noir crime drama film directed by Phil Joanou, and
starring Sean Penn, Ed Harris, Gary Oldman, Robin Wright, John Turturro, and John C.
Written by playwright Dennis McIntyre, the film was produced by Ned Dowd, Randy
Ostrow, and Ron Rotholz, with a musical score by Ennio Morricone.
Although the film was not a box office success and its release overshadowed by that of the
similarly themed Goodfellas, it was received positively by most critics.
Shot on location in New York City, the film was inspired by
the real-life Hell's Kitchen gang, the Westies.
The film explores themes of new york city, sibling
relationship, mafia boss, irish mob, crime family.
The tone is emotional and intense.